Sushma: Good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to the Bridget Management Interviews.
Sushma: I'm Sushma, HR at Omisha Foundation, Roman A4C.
Sushma: The first round of this interview starts with group discussion.
Sushma: So, in this group discussion.
Sushma: We would like to hear from you about your understanding of F4G and the role, project management intern role.
Sushma: So, what do you understand? By seeing the job description, what do you understand about us, about AFOG? And what do you understand about, project management intern role at Ohasha Foundation? Like, at AFOG?
Sushma: So I'm just giving you 3 to 4 minutes of time if you would like to note down a point to discuss.
Sushma: You can do that, and after that, any one of you plays that you are understanding.
Sushma: It's like a group discussion.
Sushma: Just share your understanding.
Sushma: And you can add a few more points from others' understanding as well, like that.
Sushma: I hope I'm clear.
Isha patel: Yes, ma'am.
Priyanka Yadav: It's not.
Sushma: Meanwhile, yeah, meanwhile, I'm thinking that, I'm hoping that everyone drop your resume, yes.
Sushma: Then you can… Take 3 to 4 minutes of time to gather the prompts.
Sushma: Okay, shall we start?
Isha patel: Thanks.
Sushma: who you would like, who would like to start? First of all, let's discuss about AFOG.
Sushma: What do you understand about APOG?
vivek shelke: Can I stop?
Sushma: Please.
vivek shelke: So, called, what I understand upon about AFOG is, it's, like,
vivek shelke: In FOG, you help, like,
vivek shelke: It's work on ethical AI governance, like mental well-being, or helping the people to adopt the AI.
vivek shelke: In this AIG1 world.
vivek shelke: So basically, you help, peoples to empower, like, youth in AI and, the technology which is going on.
Isha patel: Yes.
Priyanka Yadav: Basically, AI… A4G stands for AI for Good, goods, Impact and Collaboratives.
Priyanka Yadav: Its major focus is on governance of AI and social innovation impact without… we are developing… well, A4G is developing AI for the benefit of society, so the society and our A4G aim should work together.
Priyanka Yadav: Without causing damage to anyone.
Isha patel: Yes, ma'am, even, I've seen that A4Gs, it is essential to support people and using AI in effective manner so that we could, uplift this, socio-economic status of people by, using AI and creating jobs rather than, replacing their jobs with AI.
Harshita kerni: And now…
Sachindra Kumar: So…
Harshita kerni: Ai is responsible to create positive social impact, and especially in areas like AI governance and mental well-being, and social-economic well-being, and for the betterment of the people and the society.
Sachindra Kumar: So, which comes under Hita Foundation, which helps in, three focus areas. So, AI for governance, AI for social well-being, and, one more is AI for mental well-being. So, I think this, in all these three sectors, AI is working
Sachindra Kumar: we can take AI in better conditions, in rehabilitating the professionals, replaced by AI.
Sushma: Interrupting, your video was tucking.
Sushma: It's… it was frozing in between.
Sachindra Kumar: Ma'am, is it audible, ma'am, now?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So, operating… Yes.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, can I continue, ma'am? I'm audible.
Sachindra Kumar: Thank you, ma'am. Yes. So AI, which… AI… A4G, which comes under Omisha Foundation.
Sachindra Kumar: Which stands as.
Sachindra Kumar: AI for good. It has 3 focus areas, as it has been discussed, like AI governance, AI for mental well-being, and AI for social economic well-being. So.
Sachindra Kumar: AI for governance, which helps people in proving the things, and even AI for mental well-being, which helps the rehabilitating the professionals, especially who are replaced by the AI automation and all.
Harshita kerni: It makes the, like, AI makes it,
Harshita kerni: it makes it a little more human-centered, so that, using AI, we can solve humans' real-world challenges, while making sure that the benefits of AI reaches people and comi- community.
Isha patel: It is an initiative which also focuses on right use of AI, which is more abundant to the youth, nowadays, so that they can channelize the energies and the skills they have in a right manner by using AI, which could be potential in their growth.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, and even AI helps in the people, especially the AIC generation, to make them known in which areas to use, and how to use it, and how to use it in an efficient way.
Priyanka Yadav: It also brings… it also brings different stakeholders, such as policy makers and civil industries, societies, academics, to create more.
vivek shelke: noticed.
Priyanka Yadav: responsible and practical.
Priyanka Yadav: AIUs.
vivek shelke: And also, it helps government organizations.
vivek shelke: It also helps the government and organizations to create ethical AI policies, so it should be fair, transparent, and safe.
Harshita kerni: And the overall goal is to make AI beneficial for people, and not just productive for businesses.
vivek shelke: And it also encouraged the people from different backgrounds to participate in AI polish, like, in AI, policy discussions and everything.
Priyanka Yadav: Mehmet's focus is also on actionable outcomes, rather than just being discussed-based Evens.
vivek shelke: And it also helps for individuals to discover their new strengths and career path, with the help of AI.
Isha patel: It helps in creating opportunities rather than just replacing the existing work, and it also helps in building up sustainable ecosystem wherein all sectors and sections of people can participate up to the full potential.
vivek shelke: It also builds the communities where people support each other's growth.
Harshita kerni: It supports people developing new skills and opportunities in an AI-driven world, and it also promotes inclusive AI, so different communities can participate in shaping AI for future.
Sachindra Kumar: It also helps Eng Generation especially, not just to improve their skills specifically, but also to use the AI in an structured way, in an efficient way, which helps them in their growth.
vivek shelke: It also encourages the specialized skills that create long-term values in the life of individuals.
Harshita kerni: It also focuses on creating practical solutions, not only discussions, and it addresses changes, like, which are caused by AI, automation, and changing job roles.
Priyanka Yadav: It brings people and initiative together for social innovation.
Sushma: I would like to add above.
Sachindra Kumar: Handiri.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes.
Sushma: Yeah, go on.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, it also helps in building up their initiatives which they have built, you know, which helps them to grow more robustly in their organizations.
Sachindra Kumar: Through AI.
Sushma: Your first, like, you know, your first addressing about, FOG is, like, you know,
Sushma: Okay, it is on it. Later on, your people started giving you points based on assumptions, what I… what I felt. Alright. So, apart of that, do you like to…
Sushma: add… about Wong, what do you know, like, you know, do you have any, you know.
Sushma: background understanding about the one Harshita Foundation, something. If you would like to share that also, go ahead, or otherwise we can quickly jump into the project management.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes. So, Amisha Foundation is one of the non-profit organizations, and we're, under Amisha Foundation, two initiatives work, that is, A4G, AI for Good, and one more is Wong, which stands for Voice of New Generation. So, I can say that, A4G is a non-profit organization
Sachindra Kumar: Where, it's helping, people, to bring, good initiatives, such as AI for Good and Wong, which… and especially to say about Wong, as we discussed about A4G. So, to discuss about Wong, especially it helps the Eng Generation to raise their voices, for the,
Sachindra Kumar: for the problems, for the issues that are happening in the world right now, easily and accessibly, I can say, according to the.
Isha patel: Ma'am Wong, it stands for Voice of New Generation. It focuses on empowering the youth to understand the global social and sustainability issues, and giving them platform to express themselves and contribute towards the positive outcome of and by using AI.
Sushma: Alright, so it's enough. So, you already, you know.
Sushma: cover the point. I don't want to prolong the discussion, because I got the point from you.
Sushma: Alright.
Sushma: Now, let's discuss about project management in general. What do you understand by seeing the roles and responsibilities and key results there? Like, you know?
Sushma: key responsibilities, everything. Don't assume out of the job description, just, you know, share what you understand from the job description.
vivek shelke: So from the job description, it was clear that we will work on real social impact projects where we are to take ownership instead of following the instructions.
Harshita kerni: And the main goal is to break the, like, the goals into a small milestone, and assign responsibilities, and manage the resources and timelines as well, by identifying risk before they become problems.
Harshita kerni: And resolving issues, during execution, and also maintaining the quality, side by side.
Isha patel: Ma'am, I've seen that project management, it is a process of, taking or getting a specific role and turning it into structure, well-mannered, and,
Isha patel: well-planned exei- well-planned, form to execute in a proper way, wherein we could, work with people and, cooperate each other in work, so that we could gain the, outcome of the task in a proper manner, where we are also taking the feedbacks and assessing the risks and, using AI to identify the risk beforehand, and then, implementing the
Isha patel: So that we could… Work to the full potential and gain positive outcome of the, process.
Priyanka Yadav: Ma'am?
Priyanka Yadav: from the GD, I can clearly see that project goal… first, we have to decide the project goal, then we have to break it into the task and milestone, then assign people and resources to the particular task, and identify risk that can be… that can occur in future, and execute the project.
Priyanka Yadav: After that, we have to monitor the quality and progress of the project, and if any issue occurs. So, we have to solve the issue. Issue is something that has already occurred, so we have to solve it.
Priyanka Yadav: And after that, we have to exhilarate when necessary and complete the project successfully.
Sachindra Kumar: occurring to me, I think, as a project management intern role, as the…
Sachindra Kumar: Word itself mentions intern. So, we actually start with the initiation, then with the planning phase, then with the execution phase, then with the monitoring, and lastly comes the closing phase. So.
Sachindra Kumar: working as a project management intern here, we communicate with the stakeholders, we communicate the tasks, we assign the tasks to the team, and we communicate like a bridge between the team lead and between the clients, and between the stakeholders, I can say that, and we can be a bridge between the project
Sachindra Kumar: To be executed within time, scope, in a… in a… in a… Efficiently.
Priyanka Yadav: And ma'am, GD also mentioned ownership. That requires we have to take accountability for whatever we are doing, and we have to be… we have to be… we have to give reasons for everything.
Harshita kerni: Like, the main goal is the execution, and first we need to understand the needs that needed to be achieved, and then plan the process, and then identify the people who can act accordingly, and also gather the resources that are required, and set responsibilities and timelines.
Harshita kerni: And, also continuously track, whether they… everything is done on time and, moving, according to the plan.
Harshita kerni: And if any risk comes up, then the project manager should act early, and if an issue happens, then the project manager should make sure that the issue gets resolved and gets closed on time, so that the project doesn't get hampered.
Isha patel: Ma'am, for me, as I am a current BDS graduate, I'm a BDS graduate, and I'm currently pursuing MBA in healthcare, so for me, this opportunity helps me to turn my theoretical knowledge into the practical world, which will help me build the blueprint to get a successful future and growth.
Isha patel: Towards my academics as well.
Priyanka Yadav: Mehmet also mentioned that the events are non-IT. So, here the events will be not on software or technological-based. It will include people and social innovation, so we have to monitor people, like human resource, and we have to assure the qualities and everything.
Sushma: Anyone would like to add anything?
Sushma: Unmute yourselves, Sachindra.
Sachindra Kumar: Sorry, ma'am. First of all, I think, ma'am, we have to understand the process, whole process, how the project here works, as it is a non-IT. So, from the first to last, whatever, especially as a project manager intern, we have to be aware of the roles that we have to work in, and we have to be
Sachindra Kumar: assigning the task in a correct way, and we have to be working ourselves. Our task, for example, giving the MOEMs to the team leads, and giving the POA shields, like, for example, and everything that has to be mentioned in a recorded way.
Sachindra Kumar: And, especially if any risk occurs, we have to manage it in an efficient way.
Harshita kerni: as A2G is under the Omisha Foundation, is a non-profitable organization, so we need to make sure that the resources are limited, and the project manager needs to plan carefully, and use people according to their strengths, and identify risk early, and make sure the projects
Harshita kerni: Get delivered on time with the, intended social impact within the available resources.
Sushma: All right.
Sushma: Okay, so…
Sushma: So, about the Wong and FOG, like, you know, I have seen a close understanding from two of you, alright? So let me, quickly brief about us and project management, so that people get in clarity about us.
Sushma: So, to start this internship, anyone who are going to be, you know, giving the interview, or whomever we are going to hire. So, our policies, first of all, they have to clearly understand about us.
Sushma: And about the roles, so that you, they will be quickly get into the work, and they…
Sushma: focus everything. That's the reason we just focused in these two areas.
Sushma: So, currently, so if, if I talk about the Omisha Foundation here, Sachindra said that, it is, like, you know, we are having
Sushma: two initiators, which is Wong and FOG. Wong, which stands for Voice of New Generation, and we are focusing for the WAM, 12 to 18 group of school-going students, providing them a platform to raise their voices towards sustainability challenges.
Sushma: So, what are the sustainability challenges? They can come up some,
Sushma: You know, innovative solutions, and we increase and motivate them to put those solutions from their end in their locality.
Sushma: So that the change comes from their, from their generation, and we call them, they are the future change makers. So they are the future generation. So that's the reason we focus that is kind of growth.
Sushma: And currently, we are not much active in the work, but we will be, so far, we organize
Sushma: 7 versions of Sustaines Park events.
Sushma: Which we provide them platform, and these target, 12 to 18 is group of schools, school-going students participated, and the, like, we do have a community as well. So, this is,
Sushma: about the work, and in future, we are planning to organize more, versions of Sustainer Spark events.
Sushma: And, like, not only one day event, we are also planning to have a week event as well.
Sushma: This is about the one. And currently, we are very active, towards the AI4G initiator, which is AI for Good, Impact Collaborative, the name itself suggesting that, Impact Collaborative, AI for Good. So, if I talk about the
Sushma: mission. So, which, you know, our mission is to support individuals and communities, which is
Sushma: impacted by AI-driven changes by bringing together. We would like to collaborate, policymakers, researchers.
Sushma: donors, institution, institutions, like, etc, global leaders, who are, like, you know, working towards the good impact for air, good impact for air for good.
Sushma: So, we, we are all, you know, would like to collaborate and co-create, solutions towards our three focus areas.
Sushma: And if I talk about our vision.
Sushma: So, we build, here we, here the vision is where AI becomes the natural extension of human, human goodness. So, we believe that AI should be, should become a natural extension for human goodness. It should not be harm for the
Sushma: human, so that, you know, we can enhance the compassion, equity, and well-being, so rather than replacing the human values. So, we don't want to replace the human values because of AI. So, we want to see that,
Sushma: Ai should become a natural extension for human goodness only.
Sushma: Maintaining the equity?
Sushma: We'll be, like, you know, and compassion as well.
Sushma: This is our vision and mission. If I talk about our three focus areas, so yeah, most of people, you covered that the focus areas, which is a governance of AI, A for mental well-being, and A for socioeconomic system.
Sushma: If we talk about Air governance. So, this is our main focus thing. Here, we… Here we work.
Sushma: to make sure AI developed and used in a fair way, ethical way, and responsible way.
Sushma: So, here, we are from, we would like to, we are, you know, working towards to promote the responsible and ethical use of AI. So, and we explored the AI Swaraj, where people and communities, you know, we can have a voice
Sushma: in how AI is governed. So, here, like, you know, we would like to collaborate, I, I already said that, so we would like to collaborate with policymakers and who are working, towards the policies making with the help of AI, so that we can, you know, all together, like, you know, bringing
Sushma: experts, government, organization, and individual citizens to create AI policies that can benefit everyone. So, what are the
Sushma: policies that policymakers are coming. So, you know, we would like to…
Sushma: collaborate with the government and request in the government to look into the ethical policymaking with the help of AI.
Sushma: So that we can have a, equity, and humanity as well.
Sushma: And coming to the air for mental well-being, yeah, here our mental well-being is, focusing the job displacements, the people who are suffering for this, because of AI. Again, Sachindra covered that thing. So we, we help people
Sushma: who are affected by AI changes, discover their strengths, and build a meaningful future.
Sushma: So if I talk about the people who are, like, you know, maybe, like, you know, losing their jobs because of AI, so that, you know, we also would like to provide them a platform
Sushma: So that they can come up with the niche skills, and with the solo entrepreneurship, they can, you know, have their own, individual venture with the help of AI.
Sushma: So that, they can have a, they can have a mentally in good position, because, we, we are assuming that most of, you know, people, maybe in future, most of N youth.
Sushma: if they don't find any opportunities, most of people, immediately, they thought about the societal things and etc. Because if they didn't… if they didn't find any, possibilities to survive in the world.
Sushma: those, things, those kind of thoughts will come, will raise in their mind. So instead of that, they can also, you know, have the… if they didn't find the opportunities, they can create their own opportunities with the help of AI.
Sushma: So, and we, we increase self-awareness, personal growth, and emotional well-being in this, area for mental well-being, and using of AI, to help people grow and reach their potential, or just, you know, to increase their productivity.
Sushma: And here,
Sushma: If I talk about the socioeconomic sustainability, here, we help, people build their sustainable careers and livelihoods with the support of AI.
Sushma: And if… if I talk about, these into, you know, we…
Sushma: enable the individuals to become independent professionals or entrepreneurs using AI.
Sushma: In ethical way.
Sushma: So, in that, you know, your,
Sushma: Looking to build trusted communities where people can earn recognitions for their skills and contributions as well.
Sushma: So here, we encourage the individual of people who, like, you know, to develop specialized skills, that creating a lasting value, instead of, you know, they're blindly, simply following the present market trends.
Sushma: this is, about, us, if, if I, if I, you know, simply talk about that. So, this A4G Impact Collaborative believes
Sushma: AI should improve People's lives, and not replace them.
Sushma: And we work to ensure AI is fair, supports mental well-being, creates sustainable career opportunities.
Sushma: Will let future, you know, sustainable future for everyone.
Sushma: So, this is our…
Sushma: like, you know, a book and vision about the A4G. If I talk about the role, project management intern role.
Sushma: So let me, you know, give a clarification that this is 6 months of internship program.
Sushma: And he'll… Most of projects are into non-AT-based projects, I can say.
Sushma: If I'm telling the non-AD-based projects.
Sushma: the projects itself, like, you know, event-relevant. So, here, I, I, if you understand about the FOG, so we would like to collaborate with the people, and we have to, you know, would like to build, like, trusted communities, think tank, communities, etc. For that, we have to, you know, organize a few events.
Sushma: Like, podcast series, or, you know, some other, like, you know, sharing the ideas, like, essay contest relevance, like that, like, symposium.
Sushma: such kind of events. So, as a… you shall have to take that event as a project.
Sushma: should have to focus 3 KIs. The first one is Risk management and issue management.
Sushma: If I talk about the issue management, what are the ongoing Issues already occur and ongoing.
Sushma: You have to identify Then, and come up with some resolution plan.
Sushma: And the risk management is about anticipating the future risk.
Sushma: So that you can come up some mitigation plan for the risk.
Sushma: These are very two important, these are the, risk management, risk and issue management, or VERIC2, are the very important key result area.
Sushma: In project management at Harsha, we believe. Because if these two, like, you know, ensure risk management escalated or identified, in the right time, the whole
Sushma: Project will be in the right place.
Sushma: And a part of that, quality assurance. What are the deliverables that you're getting from your respective teams? Making sure that quality is up to the mark. And you should have to
Sushma: Set up as standard, qualities, etc. Because we believe that as a common sense skill, you can review all any kind of, you know, their deliverables, like a document, collateral, etc, whatever maybe you're getting from the team members.
Sushma: The last one is, like, you know, resource mobilization. So, what are the resources required to complete the project? You have to identify and make sure that resources is, legally available to the respective
Sushma: Team.
Sushma: Or in Doodle.
Sushma: So, here, if I talk about you, including these, You must Focus into building the stretches.
Sushma: and processors.
Sushma: Based in this processing of risk management, tissue management, quality assurance, and resource mobilization, you must be able to build a good structures and processes
Sushma: A good flow.
Sushma: Throughout the… Project.
Sushma: So this is what we're expecting from project manager, project management interns.
Sushma: it's like, you know, 30 hours of… 30 hours per week, which is Monday to Saturday. You already know everything is mentioned there.
Sushma: So now, if you would like to ask any doubts, you can go ahead, or otherwise we can move forward.
Harshita kerni: So will we use any tools regarding, project management?
Sushma: See, currently, the project managers are collaborating, with the tech team.
Sushma: for the developing of OPM tool, which is, like, you know, a good AI tool.
Sushma: which we are customizing, we are, you know, building with the help of tech team. So, it is in progress. If that is, successfully deployed, it will be deployed mostly, like, you know, in this month, mostly.
Sushma: then you will get access for that tool. So that in that tool, you can do the access of risk, issue, or everything you can manage, whole end-to-end budget management in that tool.
Isha patel: Ma'am, I have a question, like, what are the qualities that you notice or see, when a project is completed by an intern, from your perspective?
Sushma: I didn't get to a question.
Isha patel: Okay, so what are the qualities that you see, that the organization sees in the intern who has completed a particular project which is beneficial for, both the parties, like…
Sushma: Yeah, Azi, instead of… Telling about the quality, so I can say that these three KRAs…
Sushma: If the… if the individual project manager intern follows these three KRIs in their respective project, we can see a success, individual success.
Sushma: Game success, project successes.
Harshita kerni: And what will be the working structure, like, do we have to, like, is… this is an event-based, like, internship, like, we have to work according to the events. So, like, how is, like, we are going to work?
Sushma: We do have the… see, if one event is completed, so you have to plan, another event is also in, you know, in a thought. So you have to work on the scope, first of all, creating the goals, all kind of things you have to work on. So one is completed, another one will come. It's like, you know, you should not wait for…
Sushma: another event to be, you know, rolled out, like that. So it is ongoing.
Harshita kerni: Okay, so we would…
Sushma: We will be having another event in place.
Harshita kerni: So, we will have events on a daily basis?
Sushma: No, no, it's not a daily basis. See, here, if I tell about the event, for instance, now we are planning to have a podcast series.
Sushma: So that will be mostly we are planning, in this, you know.
Sushma: In this third week of the month, mostly we will start, we will give a start third week or second week of the month.
Sushma: So, maybe that podcast series should be planned 6 episodes.
Sushma: Every episode is planned, like, you know, for…
Sushma: every week, we do… if we plan one episode, so for those, period, you have to work for that podcast series, and you have to, even mostly marketing and growth team, so every project manager will be given two teams… three, three teams to work on that.
Sushma: So, in their respective teams, they need to… they need to, you know, track the progress of each individual… of the respective team members.
Sushma: Of the respective event goals. And that's a… every event is having a duration, which is one month of event, or like, you know, upcoming of event, or ongoing event, like that.
Sushma: So, mostly it will be, like, you know, one month or two months, like that. It's not, like, you know, weekly-wise or daily-wise events. It's not a… it is very difficult to scale, like, you know, to organize the event daily.
Isha patel: Yes.
Sushma: So, we usually have a particular timeline for the event.
Sushma: If we fix the timeline, maybe the timeline fix for the next month, and you have to make and choose starting at least from this month onwards, like that.
Sushma: Clear?
Harshita kerni: Okay, ma'am.
Harshita kerni: So, the projects will be the events.
Sushma: Yeah.
Harshita kerni: Okay.
Sushma: And you also will be getting, chance to work towards this, you know, OPM2 with the collaboration of tech team.
Harshita kerni: And we will, like, contact and interact with all the teams through the OPM tool.
Sushma: Yeah, exactly.
Harshita kerni: Okay.
Sushma: Anything? Oh, alright. So, quickly, please, you know, share your,
Sushma: I just want to hear from each and every one. What's your career goal?
Sushma: Why… why project management, and why FOG?
Sushma: What motivates you to do this internship?
Sushma: The four questions. The first one, what's your career goal?
Sushma: Why F4G and why project management? What motivates you to do this internship?
Sushma: Please, one by one, cover these, four questions.
Harshita kerni: So, I have chosen project management because I enjoy planning, organizing people, and doing the task, and solving problems, and taking responsibility for getting things done.
Harshita kerni: And I am also interested in working for A4G, because it combines project management with social impact and responsible AI, which is, like, the future of, like, our generation and the generation coming up, and which is the need of the all.
Harshita kerni: And the idea of working on projects where I… the final outcome can actually create value for people and society.
Harshita kerni: Also, I want to develop my skills in planning and risk and management and execution. That's why I am looking to work forward with A4G as a project manager.
Priyanka Yadav: Ma'am?
Priyanka Yadav: Ma'am, my future goal is to become a project manager. I enjoy seeing ideas convert into the, convert into the action.
Priyanka Yadav: And, I am interested in A4G because it combines two areas. That is, for… that is, project execution and social impact. I have done a research on…
Priyanka Yadav: policies that can… policies for Vixed Bharag, that is, aligned government, corporations, and,
Priyanka Yadav: individual, so that we can achieve a better objective. From there, I developed an interest in such things where I can, I can think analytically by combining all the sectors to make a more bigger objective, and to achieve it.
Isha patel: Ma'am, my long-term goal is to build career in healthcare management, where I can combine my both pasture of dental surgery background with the management skills that I am gaining through my MBA. So my experience in the academics and my publications has helped me develop interest in research, structure thinking, communicating.
Isha patel: Where I, where I could express and, take part in the, take part in,
Isha patel: Take part in, growing up, by environment.
Isha patel: And I see this project as an important skill because it involves planning, coordination, problem solving, and execution. And I chose A4G because it focuses on responsible AI and creating social impact, which is meaningful to me, as my background is in managing people and creating awareness about health.
Isha patel: So, and this internship would help me, gain practical experience in managing, real projects with developing my skills that I could later apply, for gaining, good growth and having a fruitful future.
Sushma: Being a BDS student, why did you choose your master's and MBA?
Isha patel: So ma'am, I… after completing my BDS, before getting into management, I was working as a lecturer in Dharm City Desi University. So, where my job roles include mentoring, tutoring, students, doing patient work, and along with that.
Isha patel: I had various documentation works, which, and execution of various plans where the hospital was included in, which was aligned to the policies that the government is making, for betterment of the, government and, PHCs and CHCs. So, from there, I gained more interest, and inclination towards managing
Isha patel: And developing the healthcare so that I could bridge the gap which I have seen between what the patient wants and what patient gets. So from there, I developed interest, and I took admission, in MBA healthcare management.
Sushma: Next.
vivek shelke: So, as my background is in a management degree itself, I am doing learning distance program for Manipal University, and as per my previous experience, I have organized national hackathons in India with a partnership of Physics Zwala.
vivek shelke: Then, my…
Sushma: Just please, you know, cover those four questions. Later, we will ask your experience, but.
vivek shelke: So, if I'll talk about, why I am attracted towards this internship, is, like, this role gives me greater ownership of, like, an impactful project, working on real-world problems.
vivek shelke: So, this will develop my learning and creativity, which will help me in the future, so that's why I'm interested in this internship.
Sushma: Try project management.
vivek shelke: So, as I mean…
Sushma: Project Management, and by A4G.
vivek shelke: So, basically, AFOG, because AFOG, makes some impact in society, with the AI and all, so it's helping the people, or, reforming the society, which aligns with some of my previous, experiences.
vivek shelke: where I want to grow most, and why project, product, project management is because, as I said, from starting only, I am interested in events, or organizing, or taking the leadership ownership, so the product, project management is role, where I can do these all things.
Sushma: What's your career goal?
vivek shelke: So, basically, my career goal in management is only to grow into the management area, such as in product or project management.
Sushma: And what motivates you to do this internship?
vivek shelke: So, the motivation is, like, how if, your organization is, is interacting, or, it's doing work with the AI, like, AI, making AI policies.
vivek shelke: or, teaching to the youth about AI, reforming the AI. So, which, as I also come from a technical background, so this, all things…
vivek shelke: Have been, like, attracted me more.
Sushma: Okay, next.
Sushma: Yeah, next, I think,
Sachindra Kumar: Hello?
Sushma: Yes, Sachindra Mode.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, it's audible, ma'am, clearly.
Sushma: Yeah, yeah, please.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, thank you. So, actually, my career goals lies in, project management, and where I want to experience more,
Sachindra Kumar: I want to gain more experience in project management domain, and as well as, where I have to, if I want to tell openly, I want to switch, from the tech to the…
Sachindra Kumar: project management itself, as my career lies… as I want to, have more experience in project management, and then to switch to program management. And, why especially, A4G is, I can say that, A4G lies with the new technologies, with the new innovations, and especially it helps the Internation
Sachindra Kumar: And, raising their voices, for the right things, and where also it, it, initializes with the government, initiatives, which is much better, I can say. And one more thing is, helping, like, the Eng Generation is my main goal, so I've chosen FOG to work with it.
Sushma: Why project management?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So, actually, my main strength and main goals lies in the skills of project management, and I love people, bringing people on the same page, working, bringing them to work on the same page, and I love, planning and communicating with the people, and with, doing the tasks.
Sachindra Kumar: And executing the project on time. So, this made me to… my main strength lies, which lies in project management skills, made me to choose the path of project management field.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: And what motivates you to do this internship? Did you cover this?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So, actually, as I've said, ma'am, it also helps us to gain more experience in one of these wonderful organizations, like Omisha, and which also helps us to bring value to the organization by bringing our skills to the organization itself.
Sushma: Okay. See, currently you're not pursuing, right?
Sachindra Kumar: No, I'm working as a PM intern at another organization.
Sushma: Yeah, so what's… What's the end date there?
Sachindra Kumar: Ma'am, I think within a week.
Sushma: And what's the internship tenure?
Sachindra Kumar: to 7 days.
Sushma: Okay, internship tenure there?
Sachindra Kumar: Oh.
Sachindra Kumar: I mean, it was only around, 1.5 months, like, 1.5 to around… Near one month itself.
Sushma: Okay.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: My question to you, you've already done two internships in project management, where you would like to do another internship, why not a full-time job?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. Actually, I want to gain more experience as being an intern, especially in the organizations where they provide the project management roles.
Sachindra Kumar: So, where I think that where if our foundation is strong, if our fundamental is strong, we can go, we can tackle with the things, easily, the things that we have experienced. So, I choose, to do some more months for the intern as a role, as an intern.
Sachindra Kumar: Before joining as a full-time role.
Sushma: Harshita, I think you are also currently working as an intern, right?
Harshita kerni: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: What's the internship tenure there?
Harshita kerni: It is about, 4-6 months.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Co-six months. Then what… when is your last date?
Harshita kerni: My internship will end, like, in December, but I am continuously looking for other opportunities, because the current, internship that I'm working in is not aligning with the goals and the perspective of, as a project manager that I'm looking
Harshita kerni: Like, to get in future, and also it not, helping me to gain any experience, or the skills, that will increase my management, project management career.
Sushma: See, what's your internship timings?
Harshita kerni: My internship timings over there are from 10am to 7pm, but, it is, like, flexible.
Sushma: See, my question to you is…
Sushma: You just, you know, applied here, and if, in case, if you got shortlisted, how you're going to, you know.
Sushma: Just is for those two committed internships.
Harshita kerni: like, the internship, that I'm currently working, requires me to, communicate with freelancers, like, so they, the communication with them depends on their availability and their, like.
Harshita kerni: the timings is also an issue. So, like, my internship here is flexible, and it is based on the, requirement of the freelancers and all.
Harshita kerni: And also, I'm, looking to switch for the, other internship, so I can, leave this internship midway, because it is not…
Harshita kerni: practically helping me, and also, even if they are providing me a PPO, like, there is an offer for providing PPO after this internship. But I am not looking forward to continue in this organization, because it is not aligning with the project management, as I think it is currently, like, the organization is working on hiring.
Harshita kerni: freelances and all, and I don't think so that aligns with project management.
Sushma: Is it paired internship or unpaired internship?
Harshita kerni: It is an paid internship.
Sushma: Alright,
Sushma: Okay.
Harshita kerni: And although they are paying me, like, competitively well for an internship, but still, I don't want to continue because it is not, like, beneficial for my experience or the pathway that I'm looking to move forward in project management.
Sushma: Alright. So, Priyanka, you just, you know, shared in the chat that you're doing an internship. My focus is not to, you know.
Sushma: For the internship experience, actually. We are not going as per experience, we are going as a, you know.
Sushma: Natural treatment and applicable counsel, alright. So, but I didn't see any internship that you've just done or doing in your resume, Priyanka.
Priyanka Yadav: Mama, I haven't mentioned in my resume, but I am currently doing.
Sushma: Okay, what's your current internship that you've.
Priyanka Yadav: M.
Sushma: Interning?
Priyanka Yadav: It is, about project management.
Sushma: Where? Like, is it remote or on-site?
Priyanka Yadav: on-site.
Sushma: Okay, what's the timings there?
Priyanka Yadav: Ma'am, it is, 10 to 9… 10 to 7.
Sushma: 10am to 7pm. And it's a paid internship, right?
Priyanka Yadav: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: Alright, and what's the intake for that internship?
Priyanka Yadav: Ma'am, I have joined for 3 months, but I have told them that it is not feasible for me to travel that much, so I will be quitting soon.
Sushma: They didn't complete the 3 months there, right?
Priyanka Yadav: No, ma'am. I have completed only 1 month… 1.5 months.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: So, you committed 3 months, but you're quitting in between, and Harshita also committed for 3 months, and you're quitting in between.
Priyanka Yadav: No, ma'am, I didn't commit it 3 months. I already said them that I am joining for just for experience. They have told me, if you wanted… want to quit in between, you may, but we will not provide you for the… for 15 days. So I said, okay, I… it is okay for me.
Sushma: I didn't understand. What for 15 days?
Priyanka Yadav: Ma'am, I have done for 1 month and 15 days, so they said that they will not…
Sushma: Alright.
Sushma: So, vivek, I have seen in your resume that,
Sushma: You have lots of internship experience of full intern… why again another internship?
vivek shelke: So,
vivek shelke: As I said, I am completing… still, I am not completing my bachelor's degree, that way. Taking PPA in a good company, the policy doesn't…
Sushma: your bachelors.
vivek shelke: Yeah.
Sushma: But you just mentioned it's a distance learning.
vivek shelke: Yeah, it's distance learning, but in MNCs or big companies, the policy is that for PP or CTC, the bachelor's will be completed.
Sushma: And are you working anywhere?
vivek shelke: Yeah, India,
Sushma: freelancers.
vivek shelke: Yeah, in year-lun as an operation income.
Sushma: This is the operation inter… what's your internship timings?
vivek shelke: So, it's not a fixed timing, it's flexible role, but, like, my notice period is going on, so it will be ended in a week.
Sushma: No, I just want to know the tenure of that internship.
vivek shelke: It was up 2 months, so my second month is going to end.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: And the timings?
vivek shelke: So, timing… office timings are from morning, 11.30 to evening, like, in 8.30, but again, I said the work is flexible, so it depends, like, it takes hardly one or two hours from a daily routine.
Sushma: Hmm…
vivek shelke: a little bit.
Sushma: And Isha, what's your college timings?
Isha patel: Ma'am, my college timings are, morning 7.30 to, 2.10, but, it is, I'm traveling, so it takes me around 3-30 to reach, my home.
Sushma: All right, all right. Guys, just give me, give us 5 minutes, hold on for 5 minutes, we will be back with the result, whom we are going to move forward. We'll be having the next rounds. Swetcha, just, you know, let me create a breakout rooms.
Harshita kerni: Also, ma'am, I would like to mention one thing. My internship is also work from home, and it is flexible, so…
Harshita kerni: like, I don't need to work continuously for, 10 to 7 p.m.
Sushma: Alright. Swetcha just come to the room one.
Sushma: Okay, alright.
Sushma: So… vivek?
Sushma: Harshita?
Sushma: And the… Priyanka.
Sushma: So, three of you, we appreciate your time and interest, but we are not moving forward with the next round. All the best for your future.
vivek shelke: Thank you.
Sushma: Thank you so much. Yeah, have a nice day. Three of you, I request Isha and Sachindra turn on your videos.
Sushma: All right, Harshita can leave the meeting. Thank you.
Sushma: Okay, so both of you, I don't… any one of you, can you please share that, what, like, you know, we just mentioned our stipend structure, so would you understand our stipend structure, as we mentioned in the job description?
Sushma: Any one of you?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So, as it is mentioned in the job description, it is for the 6 months of the tenure, and, first 2 months, as it is mentioned, as, 5,000, and, next it is mentioned as a 7.
Sachindra Kumar: 5, based on the rating of, 4 is to 5.
Sachindra Kumar: And next 2 months, it is mentioned as 10K. So, according to the JD, it is mentioned in this pay.
Sushma: Alright, yes. So, this is 6 months of tenure of internship. The first 2 months will be 5K. These are the benchmark of amounts. If you inverse 30 hours per week, this benchmark of amount will be created for you.
Sushma: And after… after 2 months, your first 2 months' performance will be evaluated and appraised for 3rd and 4th month, and in that rating, in that, appraisal, if you rate it out of 5,
Sushma: 4.
Sushma: So that, you can expect a benchmark of amount from 5K to $7,500, and again, if you invoice 30 hours per week, it will be given to you.
Sushma: And the same?
Sushma: Third and fourth month performance will be evaluated and appraised for 5th and 6th month. Again, your third and fourth month rating is something out of 5.
Isha patel: Fool.
Sushma: And if you invest 30 hours per week, then you can expect 7,000 per 100 to…
Sushma: 10K raised for 5th and 6 months.
Sushma: Instead, if you're not invested 30 hours per week of every month, in a month, we do have 4 weeks.
Sushma: So, if you missed off investing, you know, any one of the week also, that cannot… you cannot expect that, you know, you will get a full amount.
Sushma: Because you, you missed one week.
Sushma: Oh…
Sushma: you will be graded for the amount, for the, duration that you spend. Instead of 30 hours, you just invested 25 hours, or 20 hours. You will get amount for those 20 and 25 hours, not a benchmark of amount for that 30 hours.
Sushma: Okay? If you rated, like, you know, if not 4, we do have interns who got rating for 4 also, and they received full enrollment as well, by the way.
Sushma: And,
Sushma: like, you know, instead of 4, you got 3.53. It depends upon, like, you know, maybe 7th, instead of 7,500, maybe you will get, 7,000 or 6,500, like that. It depends upon the rating. For every rating, there is, like, you know, we do have a set of parameters. If you ask me the parameters of rating.
Sushma: So, there are two parameters. The first one is, your KRS. What are every role for your role KRS.
Sushma: Like, are you following the KRIs? Are you doing justice for your KRIs in your performance?
Sushma: And also, what are the goals given to you? Project management goals, or what are your roles, goals given to you? So, are you achieving the goals?
Sushma: Are you reaching the milestones?
Sushma: So, based on this, the performance rating will be evaluated, and the second parameter is values.
Sushma: We do have 5 core values. Integrity and authenticity, ownership and alignment, press button acceptance, and agility.
Sushma: So these are the, like, you know, innovation and imagination. So these are the five core values. We believe that, and if someone follows these five core values in day-to-day work.
Sushma: So they will average of their culture and, values, and average of performance, they will be rated out of 5.
Sushma: Any doubts in this?
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: So now, I would like to, you know, continue with the next sounds. I'm just giving you these clarifications so that I can avoid every time I cannot, you know, explain individually, so that I can
Sushma: You know, cover, things, at a time.
Sushma: So now, like, you know, Isha, please wait in the breakout room. Let me complete the session. There are, like, you know, the rest of the rounds. Please wait for 15 to 20 minutes.
Isha patel: Okay, ma'am.
Sushma: Once we are done with Sachindra, so we will take yours. Meanwhile, you can wait in the breakout room, you can turn off your video. Whenever you will be assigned in this main session, you can turn on your video, okay?
Sushma: Join roundtable.
Sushma: So, Sachindra, the current internship, you said that it's a 45 days of internship, is it right?
Sachindra Kumar: I'm actually, like, 1.5 to… it's flexible, so they have mentioned, as you can do for 1.5 also, there is no, like, any tenure and all, but… and they have mentioned also, like, you can… for… just for experience, I've asked them, and they've also mentioned, like, for 1.5 or for 2 months.
Sachindra Kumar: They have given me two options. So, I can even quit for 1.5, or else I can continue with two months of internship.
Sushma: Alright.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes.
Sushma: See, mmm… Where are you from?
Sachindra Kumar: I'm from, Gulberga, Karnataka.
Sushma: Good night to call… okay.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes.
Sushma: Congratulations.
Sushma: Do you understand Hindi or speak Hindi?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, I do understand.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Being from Karnataka, you've been able to do that.
Sachindra Kumar: I know, I do understand.
Sachindra Kumar: My native place is Gulberga itself.
Sushma: All right.
Sachindra Kumar: North Karnataka, it comes in North Karnataka.
Sushma: Okay. Tell me, how will be your career aspiration… how your career aspiration will be aligned to this internship?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So especially, I have discussed, ma'am, that my main career goals are to become a project manager, and even my main career goals lies in project management or program management, where I want to
Sachindra Kumar: Gain more experience in project management, learn more skills, and learn more, experiences, by tackling the…
Sachindra Kumar: big projects and all, and even I have a desire to gain the leadership roles, especially in, like, you know, full-time roles and all, after doing, like, sort of full-time roles for a month, for years, and even after achieving an internship. So, I think this, as a FOG, as a foundation, as… and even for the… it's a wonderful initiative for me to work in, where I can, give my best to.
Sachindra Kumar: the organization, from my skills, from my end, and even I can gain an experience, a thorough experience, by the project management work here.
Sushma: Okay.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: Are you not seriously looking for full-time roles?
Sachindra Kumar: No, ma'am, actually, as a…
Sachindra Kumar: as a BTEC student, as studying in a technical background, I gained knowledge of the technical field, but I was doing my projects and all, and I was doing my internship and all from the front end, in Bangalore and all, I came to understand that my main strength lied in project management. So.
Sachindra Kumar: Even after studying the BTEC, while studying the BTEC, I was doing the organizational work apart from the studies.
Sachindra Kumar: And where even the… even the team leads and all, were very happy, to say openly, and they… and they even awarded for the management skills and all. So, I came to know, man, that I love people bringing on the same page, and, communicating with the people, and working with the people, and more, and all. As a project management, my main skill was lying in the management
Sachindra Kumar: field itself.
Sachindra Kumar: So, I choose to, right now, for example, for 4-5 months, I wanted to do even more internships, like, I want to gain more experience, to…
Sachindra Kumar: Go into a full-time role.
Sushma: Okay, so my question is, your previous internships that you committed 3 months, and now it's kind of month.
Sushma: So, are you comfortable committing 6 months for this internship?
Sushma: You guys, bye.
Sachindra Kumar: But, yes, ma'am. So, actually, first, when I was doing as in Vid Infotech in my city itself, in my town itself, there, the project management, like, it was, somewhere out for, like, I can say that it was something, like, different, apart from the project management. So, I had to do the 3 months of it
Sachindra Kumar: humble silly. So, afterwards, coming into this, this was like a, getting into an IT itself, as a, I can say as a technical project manager, handling the projects and all, handling the IT projects and all. So, it was a bit similar with my career goals, it was matching with my career goals, where I wanted to work, and, where even, even it was very good for me, even for the non-IT also to work with.
Sachindra Kumar: with this kind of role, with a project management. So, I think that gaining around 8 months, or around 7 to 8 months, and where I did even the other certifications as well in the resume, as I mentioned, the Google Professional Project Management Certificate. So, it gave me knowledge, but I needed the practical experiences overall.
Sachindra Kumar: So, it was from the planning phase to execution phase, the courses and all. So, where I was studying about the project management in depth, as I didn't go through in my college, but after that, I had some of the practical experiences, but I needed… I experienced at least of a year.
Sachindra Kumar: to get into a good, MNC, of PM role.
Sushma: Alright. Do you have any interviews or offers in pipeline?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, I do have, like, one, but I don't want to go with that, because, A4G is a very good initiative, organization, I can say, to work in, to gain experience.
Sushma: I just want to hear, why you didn't want to, you know.
Sushma: Accept the other offer in your hand.
Sachindra Kumar: It's.
Sushma: Thank you, Chip, mum.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, it's an internship, it's not a full-time.
Sushma: Okay, and this is also an internship opportunity only now?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, but I… I searched in a, like, I came to know about the Wong, I came to know about the A4G, I researched about it. So my main career goals lied with this, and I can say that I can, work in this, I can gain a good experience, and I can add a value to the organization.
Sachindra Kumar: So I chose this one, A4G.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: What you're expecting from this internship?
Sachindra Kumar: Ma'am, especially as JD mentions, the skills and all, and the roles and all of the project manager, project manager intern to do for 6 months. So, I do think that it is a… first of all, it is a very structured way. By reading the JD itself, I came to know that it's completely focusing on the project management, project management itself.
Sachindra Kumar: And especially, the interns will be very helpful, by doing in such an organization, I can say, in such a structured organization, I can say, where we especially can gain in good experience. And, alongside, we can even contribute to
Sachindra Kumar: Through our knowledges, to the organization itself, what the organization wants from us.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: What do your father, mother do, and siblings?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. My father is a government employee.
Sachindra Kumar: He works as a KPD cell employee, and my mother is a housewife, and my sister works as a software engineer in Bangalore, in an AI company, and my brother is pursuing MBA.
Sushma: Correct.
Sachindra Kumar: Hang it.
Sushma: What's the last one statement?
Sachindra Kumar: Ma'am, it was, around, like, 10K to 12K.
Sushma: Okay, in hand, you're getting 12K work, 10K worth.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: Okay, so my question to you is, this internship, is like, you know, we already mentioned.
Sushma: Yes, ma'am. So what, so do you have any expectations, something that, or,
Sushma: You're okay with the structure, I just want to know openly.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, I'm okay with the structure and all, with the pay and all, because especially I need more experience, than the pay, especially I need the experience in project management, especially for around 4 to 5 months. So, it is a 6 months of time, I can give my best in it.
Sachindra Kumar: And, even I can learn best from it, in a structured organization, so I think it's a good one.
Sushma: Are you comfortable of starting from 5K?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, I'm comfortable.
Sachindra Kumar: And more… moreover, ma'am, actually, you know, my main, career goals as it lies within program management as well. My other… where I've came to know about the interns and all, they do not do much work with the project management.
Sachindra Kumar: But as I… as I read in the JD itself here, for the A4G, it was, mentioned about all the roles and, you know, roles which we can do, which I expected to do as a project manager intern, before getting into full-time.
Sachindra Kumar: So, I chose this…
Sushma: Here as a project manager, you, or you will be, you know, added in the enabler state, which is, you know, you have to enable the entire organization. It is not, you know, a small responsibility. It's a… it's like, you know, whose responsibility as a project manager, you have to look up for that.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: Oh… Alright, any questions you would like to ask us?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, like, if you have been shortlisted and selected, how will the success look like in,
Sachindra Kumar: First 90 days, or, like, first 3 months.
Sachindra Kumar: For an intern.
Sushma: Yeah, the first one is…
Sushma: Like, you know, once you've adapted to the environment, if you start working.
Sushma: Focus the KRIs of project management.
Sushma: try to… Will these structures or process So that…
Sushma: You will be individually going to be success.
Sushma: An organization can, you know, you can, you can contribute
Sushma: Very much to the organization.
Sushma: Because we are looking for a project manager, Who can be able to…
Sushma: put into the action, like, what is the risk management, issues management, KRS, what are the KRS? Not only in the votes.
Sushma: Should we put in the progress? Should we put in the actions?
Sushma: A bagel?
Sushma: Muralid structures.
Sushma: Processes.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: This is what we are expecting. If you can do that.
Sushma: You can, you know, eventually see a good success.
Sushma: And you will be appreciated, and in the performance visor also, you will be rated group.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. I make sure that I'll do my best, ma'am, where, as even, like, studying as a BTEC student, I had main intentions on the project management itself, where I would work,
Sachindra Kumar: like, around the clock and all in the other organizations, like a PM, like an organization manager. So, by seeing that,
Sachindra Kumar: my main goal was to work in this field itself. So I make sure that I'll do my best in this organization also.
Sushma: People, when we ask the project management, they will say from planning to execution, but actually, what we are expecting from project managers.
Sushma: Execution? What structures you're going to build?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, yes, ma'am.
Sushma: What process you're going to introduce?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: This is what our focus is.
Sachindra Kumar: No.
Sushma: Like, you know, if you focus these, so you can, you know, gradually see a good growth. This, I can say that so far, what I have seen from the people.
Sachindra Kumar: How can I show.
Sushma: Yeah, so, yes, Swetcha says please take over this initial deadbeat. Over to you.
Swetcha: Alright, hi, Sachindra, my name is Swetcha, and I'm the HRBP at A4G. I'll be asking you questions related to your natural fitment, moving forward.
Sachindra Kumar: Amen.
Sachindra Kumar: Good afternoon, map.
Swetcha: would have them on higher purpose.
Swetcha: So, what type of work or project feels hardest to you for you to manage, and how do you organize it so it doesn't feel overwhelmed?
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am?
Sachindra Kumar: So, hardest,
Sachindra Kumar: if I can say, I cannot, directly make it as a hardest, unless and until, I've gone through it and, I've experienced it. But I'll make sure that,
Sachindra Kumar: I'm going to… do it in a structured way. I'm gonna do, if needed.
Sachindra Kumar: Communication is needed to the seniors, communication is needed to the stakeholders. I'll,
Sachindra Kumar: surely communicate with them, and if from my end, if I cannot do that task specifically, I'll make sure that, I'm going to take the help of my, seniors, and, I'm gonna do research first that where I'm lagging behind, or if where I am, I'll make sure that if I have to improve in any of the specific
Sachindra Kumar: like, Things and all.
Sachindra Kumar: So, and I'll make sure that none of the things will seem harder, because I've chosen this as a project manager itself. It's my role to do my best, to know about the things, and to go through the things.
Swetcha: So, in a remote or team-based work, what are some problems you've seen that don't show up immediately but cause trouble later?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So…
Sachindra Kumar: as in a remote place, first of all, yes, there are not much disadvantages, but as we can say that, if some of the members or some of the team members are not going to, join, are not going to, for example, while working, in the last intern, as a PM intern in the last organization, some of the members, if they didn't join, it was my
Sachindra Kumar: work, to collaborate with them, to make sure that why they are not going… when they're not joining, if any… some issues have occurred, if any urgency has occurred. In that way, they were not able to communicate with me as a PM, and if they were not able to join the meet, so I made sure that I made them, about them to tell to the team leads, to the HRs.
Sachindra Kumar: So that there was no gap in between the, me and with the team.
Swetcha: How do you usually regain control when you start feeling overwhelmed?
Sachindra Kumar: Sorry, ma'am.
Swetcha: How do you usually regain control when you start feeling overwhelmed with your work?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So first of all, I'm not going to take it as a negative way.
Sachindra Kumar: When I feel overwhelmed, but I'm going to see the things in which made me overwhelmed, so that I will not take it as a negative way, as you said, I'll take it in a positive way, so that I will improve myself, I'll give my best.
Sachindra Kumar: And I have chosen this path. I will make sure to know that each and every work is in a structured way, is in a collaborative way, is in a way which helps the organization, so that from my end, there will be no issues and no problems, and I'll make sure that the work is in a quality way, and everything is aligned with what the organization seeks.
Swetcha: What will be the first step that you take in a situation like this?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. First of all, the first step which I take is that I will make sure why… what is the root cause
Sachindra Kumar: for this. What is the route that has caused this situation?
Sachindra Kumar: In this project.
Sachindra Kumar: So, I'm going to break it down, and I'm going to see that it should not be repeated again, but first step, which I'm going to take, is I'm going to improve on that. And I'm not going to stop, like, my work because of this, but I'm going to be in that line itself.
Sachindra Kumar: as a PM, and I'm going to improve myself more and more, so that even the projects and all will be running smoothly.
Swetcha: Tell me about a responsibility you took that lasted overtime, not just one time task. How did you ensure that it got completed properly?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So, can I use some of the examples, ma'am, in this? Like, from… yes, ma'am, yes, ma'am. So, from the last, I was working as a PM intern.
Sachindra Kumar: Some of the examples I can take as, I worked on the projects, and it were, like, 2-3 IT projects, which a team was working.
Sachindra Kumar: And, especially, there were teams, like UI UX teams were there, front-end, back-end teams were there, software QA teams were there, and I made sure that they all gave the
Sachindra Kumar: every day the updates, and make sure that the PO sheet was maintained, and what every plan should be taken in a weekly basis, and in a monthly basis, and I made sure that
Sachindra Kumar: every single day, even the… from the attendance, and from till the execution phase, whatever, every documentation was… has to be maintained from a PM, from the end of the PM.
Swetcha: I end up.
Sachindra Kumar: And, and… hello?
Swetcha: I can hear you.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, actually, my voice was repeating.
Sachindra Kumar: Sorry for that, ma'am.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. And I'll make sure that, from my end, the documents are maintained in a structured way, in a correct way, and even every team's will be accessible to the documents.
Swetcha: Have you ever questioned a rule, process, or instruction because it didn't make sense what happened in a situation like this?
Sachindra Kumar: Ma'am, can you please repeat it once more? Your voice was breaking a bit.
Swetcha: Alright, so my question was, have you ever questioned a rule, process, or instruction because it didn't make sense? And what happened in a situation like this?
Sachindra Kumar: Okay.
Sachindra Kumar: But, yes, ma'am, in the work, actually, I didn't, question, in that way, but I made sure, that,
Sachindra Kumar: Everything was being done what the team wanted it to be done.
Sachindra Kumar: So, I made sure that it was what we are doing, whether it was aligned with the priorities of the project, with the timelines of the project, with the scope of the project, with the deliverables of the project, and I made sure that it was executed in the right way.
Swetcha: Okay,
Swetcha: Could you tell me about a time where you simplified a task that was overcomplicated? Like, how do you simplify something that's already overcomplicated?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, no.
Sachindra Kumar: So, some of the tasks, yes, they were a bit complicated. If I say it in a, structured way, in a star method, if the situation and all.
Sachindra Kumar: So I mainly go through, first is the situation, if the situation is in a complicated way. So, I'll see what… first… first the point, first main point is thing… is a thing that I'm gonna see what… what my situation is there, in this, and what my task will be.
Sachindra Kumar: And according to that, I'm going to take the actions in an efficient way, so that even the team will not be affected. And, for example, if I say from my last project.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, they were a new joinees in our team, but, they were also some of the issues with the, like, not kind of issues, but there was a technical glitch, like, 2 to 3 days of the time. And it was a complicated thing, like, the senior has, especially the PM has to see that the seniors has to, like,
Sachindra Kumar: give back all the documentations, for the new joinees in our team. So, for… if I'm, saying an example, that around, like, between two… yes, two weeks before itself, this thing has happened. So, the tech… the senior was unable to,
Sachindra Kumar: hand over the documents in a correct way, so… but I had to tell the team lead what has to be done till the Saturday, like, till one week.
Sachindra Kumar: So, around 2 days, it was, like, a delay in that, because the senior was something, facing the technical issue, but I made sure that the new joine was having every document, especially, like, description of the project, especially for 2 days to go through as a new joine to understand the description of the project, and I made my best to make sure to the new joinee
Sachindra Kumar: that, they should not be wasting their time, as a… as a new journey in the, like, for two days. So I made even sure that afterwards, for the senior, to, to hand over the projects in a…
Sachindra Kumar: Timeline way.
Sachindra Kumar: So that was a complicated thing, that, that has occurred.
Sachindra Kumar: And that was the actions that I took, ma'am.
Swetcha: Okay, so now we'll ask you some questions related to the organizational fitment. What's something people usually rely on you for?
Sachindra Kumar: Sorry, ma'am.
Swetcha: What is something people usually rely on you for?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am, actually, to say that I'm very, it's not like I'm boasting, but to say that, I encourage people a lot, because I had gone through a time where, I lacked the encouragement in my life.
Sachindra Kumar: During my, I can say, my BTEC, between my studies and all, because I thought this, indeed the parents are there to encourage us, and indeed, they are the ones who make us the person who are in, who are we in our lives.
Sachindra Kumar: But there were some of the peoples, I'm not going to speak negative of them, or not going to focus on them, but yes, we have to be encouraged a lot, so I make sure that… I'll make people encouraged in the work, I'll make them… I'll make sure that I've said before itself in this interview, I'll make sure that the people are working on the same page.
Sachindra Kumar: In the same project, for the same goal.
Sachindra Kumar: So, I encourage people a lot, and many of my friends also say that they call me, and whatever, if they are going through hardships and all.
Sachindra Kumar: They'll tell me, they'll speak with me, and they'll share their thoughts and problems with me, so that, yes, I will say to them, and I'll encourage them, as I've gone through, through that situation, so that even they should be encouraged. So this, this was one of the things that people, my friends, usually depend on.
Swetcha: When someone interrupts you repeatedly, what do you usually do in that moment?
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am. So, someone interrupts me repeatedly. I'm not going to take it in a negative way, first of all.
Sachindra Kumar: But first of all, I'm going to see that my work is not being get disturbed, especially, like, the organizations like A4G and all. And one more thing is, I'm going to see what they want from me.
Sachindra Kumar: And I'm going to see why they want that thing from me. Any of the things, whatever it may be. And I'm going to see that… how much is the urgency that they need their thing from me, so that, if they're irritating, or if they are, repeatedly asking me that thing. So, according to that basis.
Sachindra Kumar: I'm going to… Like, response to them.
Swetcha: Okay. What part of change do you struggle with the most?
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am. So, first of all,
Sachindra Kumar: I think a change is a very good thing in our life, so unless and until, there is no change, there will be no new experiences in our lives.
Sachindra Kumar: So, one more thing is, yes, a bit… when… when we start doing a new thing, yes, it, seems… it doesn't seem familiar, everything with us, but it does,
Sachindra Kumar: changes some of the things, like our daily routines, like our daily things that we do. But when we get familiar with that, and when we know that why it is being done in our lives, and why it has to be done properly.
Sachindra Kumar: So, I think that instead of challenge, I take it as an opportunity in my life to learn new things, to learn new perspectives, and yes, that's it, ma'am.
Swetcha: Okay.
Swetcha: What's the value you refuse to compromise on, even if it costs you?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. So, actually,
Sachindra Kumar: I'm, a person of, timely structure, and even if it costs me something, like, for the work, especially, for example, if I'm committing to any of the things as working in a PM intern, either in this organization or in other organizations, I'll make sure that what I committed, I'm going to do it.
Sachindra Kumar: From my best end. From my knowledge, and from my, like…
Sachindra Kumar: From what I can do my best, so that I'll make sure it, that, if something also it costs me, but I promise it, I will do it, so I'll make sure it… I'll surely do it on a timely basis.
Swetcha: Okay, thank you. That was it for my questions. Sushma Anita?
Sachindra Kumar: Thank you, ma'am.
Sushma: Oh, yes.
Sushma: So, I just want to listen from you.
Sushma: So you've done, two internships, the… including the current internship and the past internship in project management.
Sushma: Could you please quickly share the insights or knowledge you gained from those internships?
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am. So first of all, doing from that, internships.
Sachindra Kumar: I came to know that communication is very, essential thing in project management, and without communication, yes, it's, we cannot achieve any of the things, especially in this field, as project management. And, it taught me to do the works in a structured way, instead of doing it in an assumption way.
Sachindra Kumar: So that it will add value to the company, it will add value to the people in the organization, and it will also add value to the organization itself.
Sachindra Kumar: So, and one more thing, I can say, ma'am, apart from this, is, I learned the new skills and the new, like, technologies and all, in a behavioral way.
Sushma: we'll have a book.
Sachindra Kumar: So that,
Sachindra Kumar: Making people happy and making them, like, supporting them in their weaknesses and all, makes us very happy, especially in this role.
Sachindra Kumar: So, that was some of the things that I learned from my past internships.
Sushma: Alright.
Sushma: See, are you willing to… Kamit ang Kupak, are you willing…
Sushma: To commit, or comfortable to commit.
Sushma: For next 6 months, if you got shortlisted, for the next 6 months, Monday to Saturday, 5pm to 9pm.
Sushma: So, if I'm telling the 5pm to 9pm, it's like 4 hours only coming. But,
Sushma: The 5 p.m. to 4… also, 5am to 9pm, that what we are expecting from the committed interns will be?
Sushma: So we do have team meetings. You said that without communication, we can't do anything.
Sushma: So it's not invaluable, it's a team meeting.
Sushma: So, the concept understandings they can gain from the operational leaders, the team meetings will be that. And your, your respective team, what are the teams that you assign to manage the project manager, you have to attend those meetings also, so that you will get to know.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: What are the current things happening in that game?
Sushma: So, all these team meetings, most of you will be scheduled in between of this window, which is 5pm to 9pm.
Sushma: You can do the same work, back-end work, which is your sheet updation, or doing the quality check, or the other things.
Sushma: We can do your flexible time, like, in the morning, afternoon, the midnight. It's up to you. But 5pm to 9pm.
Sushma: Your presence is very required. Your activeness is very required to the hitchas and yoga teams.
Sushma: Can you be able to commit to this?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. I'm able to commit, completely for the 6 months, like, from 9 to… 5 to 9, sorry.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: Oh, you mean we did join, Mel?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am.
Sushma: See, so if you got shortlisted, we will let you know.
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am.
Sushma: Yes, another round will be there with operational leader.
Sushma: If you crack that round.
Sushma: Then, you know, we will, look into your onboarding steps, and we will… we will brief you, what… how will be your onboarding steps, everything.
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am, sure.
Sushma: Could you please drop your contact number and email address in this chat box?
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, ma'am. Oh.
Sachindra Kumar: Ma'am, one doubt I had, that, will the round…
Sachindra Kumar: will be taking place today itself, or, either some other day, mah?
Sushma: Monday, Monday, mostly Monday, not Tuesday.
Sachindra Kumar: Oh.
Sushma: Funding money.
Sachindra Kumar: Yes, as the JD was mentioned, that, in one single day, the three rounds would be there, so…
Sushma: Actually, that's the thing, you completed the J…
Sushma: Group discussion, natural fitment and organizational equipment, everything is there.
Sachindra Kumar: Okay.
Sushma: So, this is for today's interview. The interview process is closed, but the last final confirmation round will be taken by the operational data.
Sachindra Kumar: Operational leader. Okay.
Sushma: Yeah.
Sachindra Kumar: Welcome back.
Sushma: We gotta come. Yeah.
Sushma: Anything else? Any doubts?
Sachindra Kumar: No, ma'am, I think I'll get… I'll be notified regarding…
Sushma: Drop… yeah, yeah, you will be notified, you will be notified either from email, or you will get a call from us.
Sushma: Drop your email address as well.
Sachindra Kumar: Okay, ma'am, sure.
Sachindra Kumar: Aw.
Sachindra Kumar: I have a date, ma'am.
Sushma: Okay, thank you. You can…
Sachindra Kumar: Thank you, ma'am. Thank you so much.
Sushma: Both of you.
Sachindra Kumar: Thank you so much.
Sushma: See, what do you think?
Sushma: He's what we're doing.
Swetcha: That is a good fit.
Sushma: Oh, okay.
Swetcha: the accurate answers for all the questions I asked.
Sushma: Let's check, huh? If you didn't satisfy the natural refutement.
Sushma: Let's, you know, discuss, and we can ask her to live.
Sushma: if he… if he… if she's good to go after taking the natural fit, then you can, you know, immediately take the organizational field. If you feel that he's…
Sushma: She is, you know, naturally fits for that problem.
Swetcha: We're Welcome. It's almost time for WorkHub also.
Sushma: Yeah, I will tell the project manager to look after that. We can rapid this, and we can join 10 minutes or 20 minutes later.
Swetcha: So first, we need to take the natural fit foil.
Sushma: Yeah, yeah.
Swetcha: Oh, bye.
Sushma: Isha, where are you from?
Isha patel: Ma'am, I'm basically born and brought up in, Reliance, Jamnagar, but I'm native to Anand.
Sushma: Okay.
Sushma: What do your father, mother do, and siblings?
Isha patel: Yes, so my father is a chemical engineer. He's working in Reliance Industries Limited. My mother is an BA, LLB graduate, but she's currently not practicing, and my brother is working as a software engineer.
Isha patel: In Ahmed Ahmedabad Private Company.
Sushma: Okay, just give a minute.
Sushma: Tell me what,
Sushma: How your career aspiration will be aligned to this, internship, or to this organization?
Isha patel: So ma'am, through this, internship,
Isha patel: That has been provided to me from the platform, which is basically oriented more towards the social impact.
Isha patel: Of AI. So, as in when we know that the, AI is being incorporated or embedded in each and every, aspects of lives, even in the healthcare. So, via this project, I'd be able to learn about using AI, and secondly, I would be also learning about taking accountability, responsibility, and ownership, where I will be able to plan, execute, coordinate.
Isha patel: various, events, the projects that would be assigned to me. So this will help me in developing, the typical, managerial,
Isha patel: traits that I'm being taught, as in my theory classes, so this will help me gain practical, knowledge, and which I would be able to apply, into my blueprint towards my, goal and, aspiration in the future career.
Sushma: Oh.
Sushma: Okay, so you said that you pra- you,
Sushma: long-term goal will be healthcare. Are you doing MBA in healthcare?
Isha patel: Yes, ma'am, I'm doing MBA in healthcare management.
Sushma: Then why project management?
Isha patel: So, ma'am, in project management, the core skills, for both of them are same. That is the managerial skill, that is planning, execution, coordination, cooperating, communication with people. So, the core of the…
Isha patel: Manager is same for, either for healthcare or project management, and if I'm looking in healthcare, so there also, I have
Isha patel: I, want to go for the various projects in the government that are being held, so this project management will align me towards the project management that I want to go future in the healthcare aspect.
Sushma: Will you please share with what do you understand about project management?
Isha patel: So, ma'am, basically, in project management, I understand that if a task is given, I have to understand about the goal, objective, and, goal and objective of the project, where I will be, breaking down into… it into planning, execution, coordination.
Isha patel: And, later on, onto the execution, where I would be take, taking responsibility and accountability of the work that is to be…
Isha patel: are done, and that I have to be taking it from others.
Sushma: What you're expecting from this internship?
Isha patel: So, ma'am, from this internship, I'm expecting that I would gain practical knowledge of the theory that I'm learning, and this will help me, build a blueprint towards the future goal that I'm aspiring to, and I would learn various skills that I have mentioned, ahead, in the,
Isha patel: In the previous questions about the planning, execution, coordinating, and Communication, with people.
Sushma: Why can't you do the internships which is, you know, relevant to the healthcare?
Sushma: Why is something, you know, in project management?
Isha patel: So, ma'am, in project management, there are the skills which are same as in the healthcare management projects. So, if I'm talking about project management, I am looking towards going into the policy-making and the policy projects of the government.
Isha patel: So, this project management, being a non-IT project, it will help me towards more broad and better understanding of a project, and working as a manager to learn and acquire the skills which I would be able to inculcate and effectively use towards my goals.
Sushma: Oh.
Sushma: Tell me your last one, step in.
Isha patel: Sorry, ma'am?
Sushma: Last drawn stipend.
Isha patel: Last round stipend.
Sushma: Stipend, stipend, yeah.
Sushma: From your previous intention.
Isha patel: I do not have previous internship. Like, I was inter… dental intern, so at that time, it was the, private, so we were supposed to get 10,000 to 15,000, but we were,
Isha patel: sign that we are giving it to the foundation, so we donated all of our, in that, but as in when I was, doing my, lecture, so a lecturer job at that time, I was getting 25K, per month.
Sushma: Just give me a minute.
Isha patel: Okay, ma'am.
Isha patel: Ma'am, you're not audible.
Sushma: Do you have any questions, Isha?
Isha patel: No ma'am, I just had a doubt about the skills part that I have asked you earlier, so that was the only thing I had.
Sushma: skills part. See, here the skills is, like, you know, for project management, whatever you thought about the project management.
Sushma: I was thinking that you… it's not, up to the mark that you're understanding. You… you're seeing the healthcare… you're just seeing the management, the management, management, you know, if that aligns, you know, you can do a project management, but project management is not like that. So…
Sushma: You do have to, you know, able to… Design the stretchers.
Isha patel: Yes, yes, I understand.
Sushma: The process is true.
Isha patel: That's true.
Sushma: If I talk about that, you can be able to anticipate the future risk.
Sushma: So…
Sushma: I was thinking that whatever you just, you know, telling that healthcare, you know, will be aligned to the project management.
Sushma: I still couldn't, you know, convince that, it… because I was feeling that there is not much alignment in the healthcare and project management.
Sushma: That is what I would like to say, that's it.
Sushma: Any questions you would like to ask?
Isha patel: No, ma'am.
Sushma: Oh, okay.
Sushma: So… That's clear sheep.
Sushma: Why a… why particularly, like, you know, you would like to do, a project management? Why not a… another… there is marketing management is there, or, like, human resource management is there? Can you please break that?
Isha patel: So ma'am, project management, in project management, I, it starts from understanding, getting a project, and understanding the core of the project. So, it starts from understanding the project.
Isha patel: Then into planning, and then into segregating it into various small parts where it is divided, and so that
Isha patel: We, and accordingly, that if we work, so at that point of time, if it is divided, so the risk also is divided. So, if we do, everything is done, by, just in a planned manner, so the risk.
Isha patel: that comes into is, it will get reduced, so it, so if, if there are any chances to.
Isha patel: do any mistake that won't be as much as prevalent as if it is done completely. So, the segregation, the segregation and then the execution part. So, if it is segregated and divided well, if each part is done well coordinate… in coordinated, manner.
Isha patel: So the execution that we'll get, would also be the best of what we can and what we have achieved.
Sushma: Alright, see, review contact number, an email address, so if you got shortlist, like, you know, if you got shortlisted, you will get here from us.
Sushma: If you didn't get any, you know, any mail or any callbackers, you can assume that we just moved with someone else.
Isha patel: Okay, ma'am.
Isha patel: So, ma'am, I have to share my email ID.
Sushma: Yeah, email ID and contact number.
Isha patel: In the chat box.
Sushma: Yeah.
Isha patel: Okay, ma'am.
Sushma: Okay, thank you.
Isha patel: No, no.
Sushma: Do it again, yeah.
Isha patel: Thank you, thank you, ma'am.
Sushma: Have a nice day, yeah.
Isha patel: Thank you, ma'am.